

Throughout my studies and work experiences, I have honed my problem solving ability, developed several skills, faced fast-paced environments.

I am a contributor to many open source projects: I firmly believe that collaboration is the key to innovation

## Experience

#### DevOps & Technical Product Owner @ hiop

Oct 2021 - Today

- Co-creator of several components that led to the company's flagship product: an high-performance data processing mesh platform that enables DaC, quickly high-value data provision and data-driven decision making
- Co-creator of an HPC infrastructure on which relies real-time AI-based applications
- Designer and maintainer of company's CI/CD pipelines
- Creator and maintainer of several libraries on which the company's codebase relies
- Co-led growth, training and knowledge sharing among the team, which increased from 5 to 15 people

## Full Stack Developer @ CNRs Institute of Biophysics

Dec 2020 - Aug 2021

Collaborator involved in the *Human Brain Project* with the aim of developing a Python and JS-based web application named *NeuroFeatureExtract* to analyse electrophysiological features

#### Bioinformatics Trainee @ ISMETT

May 2021 - Jul 2021

Practitioner on efficient algorithms and technologies to analise biological sequences represented in FASTA format, as part of a university internship project

# Collaborator of ML Research Project @ UNINA

Nov 2019 - Mar 2020

Research project with the aim of developing a Python-based ML fuzzy classifier to diagnose celiac disease in Sicilian and Maltese children

# Full Stack Developer Trainee @ Informamuse

Jan 2019 - Mar 2019

Web Developer as part of a university internship project

#### Education

# Double Master in Computer Science @ UNIPA & UGE

Sep 2019 - Oct 2021

Double Master achieved cum laude with final thesis about RDF data and columnar formats

ECTS: 120/120 GPA: 29.29/30

#### Bachelor in Computer Science @ UNIPA

Sep 2016 - Aug 2019

Bachelor achieved cum laude with final thesis about suffix array data structure

ECTS: 186/180 GPA: 29.00/30

# Erasmus Exchange @ ELTE

Sep 2018 - Jan 2019

Outstanding study experience which gave the opportunity to improve a vast set of skills

| Others                           |             | Publication   |  |
|----------------------------------|-------------|---|--|
| CMM Pre-doctoral Research School | Aug 2020    | The EBRAINS NeuroFeatureExtract: An Online              |  |
| ESS Information Science School   | Set 2019    | Resource for the Extraction of Neural Activity Features |  |
| Scientfic High School Diploma    | 2012 - 2016 | From Electrophysiological Data                          |  |

#### Skills

| Certifications               | Languages       | Workflow                     |
|------------------------------|-----------------|------------------------------|
| AWS: Practitioner, Developer | Italian: native | Bash, Git, Docker, CI/CD     |
| Data Science                 | English: $B2$   | Rust, Python, Java, Scala, C |
| GCP: Digital Leader          | French: $A2$    | AWS, GCP                     |
| GitHub: Foundations Actions  |                 |                              |